

Job Nda Nmadu

Professor of Agricultural
Economics, Fellow of the
Nigerian Association of
Agricultural Economics (NAAE)

https://www.jobnmadu.com/



https://github.com/JobNmadu



job.nmadu@gmail.com

https:/linkedin.com/in/JobNmadu

CAREER SUMMARY

An experienced academic with more than three decades of industry experience in research, teaching and community development

Have led applied economic research in trend analysis and forecasting; climate change; technical efficiency; environmental sustainability and computable general equilibrium

FUNCTIONAL SKILLS

Statistics, Research Methods and Econometrics Modeling, data science, machine learning

#1

#2

#3

Adaptive computer programming using R, RStudio and General Algebraic Modeling System (GAMS), R package development

Innovative and creative data analysis and visualization, consultancies

WORK EXPERIENCE

Federal University of Technology, Minna, Nigeria, 2006 - Present

Professor & Researcher, Dean, Industrial Liaison Officer, Director, Head of Department: Responsible for general coordination of the School and Department, leading researches and serving as consultants to various local and international organisations as well as advisor to more than 100 students (undergraduates, Masters and Doctorates) and the coordination of students skills acquisition Office as well as Director in the Quality Assurance and Productivity Office.

The Federal Polytechnic, Bida, Nigeria, 1992 - 2006

Chief Lecturer, Acting Head of Department and SIWES Coordinator: Lecturing, researches, general administration and Committee membership.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Consultant and Socio-Economic expert for Environmental Impact Assessment (EIA) of Etisalat base stations in 16 states of Northern Nigeria (2010-2012); Environment Audit of AshakaCem Plc (2012); Adoption of Technologies by Niger State Fadama III beneficiaries (2013); Assessment of Private Extension Services Providers in Niger State under FGN/IFAD Value Chain Development Programme (2016); Needs Assessment of IFAD-VCDP LGAs in Niger State (2017) and proposed LGAs in Niger State (2019). International Panel for Climate Research for Development (CR4D) Fellowship by the Africa Academy of Sciences, Nairobi, Kenya (2019). Socio-Economic Expert in EIA Panel Review Meetings of some development projects on behalf of the Federal Ministry of the Environment (2009-2019) Niger State Coordinator and Collaborator for the USAID funded

EDUCATION

Ahmadu Bello University, Zaria, Nigeria

BSc 1987

MSc 1998

PhD 2002

TRAINING

- Introduction to Data Science, 2020
- Econometrics for Policy Analysis Using Stata, 2017
- Practical General Equilibrium Modelling with GAMS, 2016
- GTAP101: Introduction to Computable General Equilibrium Modelling, 2016
- Web 2.0 Learning Opportunity, 2014
- Advanced Leadership Seminar,
 2006
- Diploma in Data Processing and Computer Programming, 1995

Research Interests

Country-wide economic analysis of efficiency (CGE) and resource allocation, Environmental Impact Assessment (EIA); impact of climate change adaptation on incomes and productivity, resources efficiency and livelihood of small-scale farmers in Nigeria and Africa

THANK YOU

for viewing the summary of my CV

PROF. JOB NDA NMADU